<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>The Symphony of Data on Social Informatics</title><link>https://LivDreyer.github.io/CSS24_ProjectB/</link><description>Recent content in The Symphony of Data on Social Informatics</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="https://LivDreyer.github.io/CSS24_ProjectB/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Data description</title><link>https://LivDreyer.github.io/CSS24_ProjectB/data-description/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://LivDreyer.github.io/CSS24_ProjectB/data-description/</guid><description>To address the research question, &amp;ldquo;What is the relationship between artist collaboration patterns, popularity, and lyrical expression of genre themes?&amp;rdquo;, acquiring comprehensive data on artists is essential.
Figure 1: Main Data Sources.
We utilize data from APIs such as Spotify and Genius, supplemented by a Kaggle dataset, as the cornerstone of our analyses. This data collection process resembles a &amp;ldquo;chain reaction&amp;rdquo;, where Kaggle&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;US Top 10K Artists and Their Popular Songs&amp;rdquo; dataset serves as the starting point.</description></item><item><title>Network analysis</title><link>https://LivDreyer.github.io/CSS24_ProjectB/network-analysis/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://LivDreyer.github.io/CSS24_ProjectB/network-analysis/</guid><description>The purpose of the network analysis is to highlight the underlying mechanism of the Spotify Network and tendencies between artists when they collaborate with each other.
Degree Distribution: This analysis of the degree distribution, comparing our artists collaboration network to a random mirroring network, shows that the real network of artist collaborations exhibits non-random patterns, meaning artists are not connected purely by chance.
Assortativity: There was found no major indications that popularity was correlated with a higher number of features.</description></item><item><title>Text Analysis</title><link>https://LivDreyer.github.io/CSS24_ProjectB/text-analysis/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://LivDreyer.github.io/CSS24_ProjectB/text-analysis/</guid><description>The textual analysis of song lyrics is used in our project to investigate distinctive themes and language patterns across different genres. This approach is interesting for several reasons:
Genre-Specific Themes: We would like to see if it is possible to identify genre-specific characteristics/themes. Analyzing these differences should help to define what sets the genres apart.
Comparative Analysis: By looking into the frequency and context of words within genres, we can identify which themes and words are predominant for each genre.</description></item></channel></rss>